A Guide to the Rudy Nothdurft Collection of Newsom-Newsome-Nuzum Family Genealogical Records
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Rudy Nothdurft Collection of Newsom-Newsome-Nuzum Family Genealogical Records
The Library of Virginia
43744
3 cubic feet (3 boxes)
Nothdurft, Rudolph J., 1927-
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Rudolph J. Nothdurft, Jr., Richland, South Carolina, 22 April 2008.
Scope and Content
Genealogical research files of Rudolph J. Nothdurft, Jr. (1927- ), focusing on the Newsom-Newsome-Nuzum family, mostly of the Southeast and Midwest. The bulk of the collection consists of correspondence between Nothdurft and others who either had or sought information on the family, and copies of primary source documents gathered during his research. Also included are two bound compilations done by Nothdurft, Compiled Histories of Newsom, Newsham, Newsum, Newsome, and Nuzum Families Who Came to America, and The Newsom Newsome Family Genealogy and History, both completed in 2004.
Arrangement
Collection is maintained in the original folder groupings established by Rudolph J. Nothdurft, Jr. The file folders retain the same labels as his originals. Additional information recorded in the Contents List was copied from Nothdurft's notes on the original file folders. The folders have been arranged alphabetically, with a separate section at the end for folders labeled with state name abbreviations. By and large, Nothdurft organized these notes under the name of the person from whom he received information, or for whom he provided information, not according to the individual or individuals being researched.
Contents List
- The Rudy Nothdurft Collection of Newsom-Newsome-Nuzum Family Genealogical Records. (Box 1-3)
  - Anderson, Carolyn. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    "Nathaniel Newsom, Elizabeth Ann Whitehead"
  - Bawcum, Max and Ima. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    "Green Berry Newsom VA"
  - Boone, Louise Vann. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    "I never met Louise Vann Boone because she had passed on. She did leave behind some of her good research. RJN"
  - Bransflakes [email screen name]. (Box 1, Folder 4)
    "TX, CA, Brandy? in CA"
  - Brown, Cheryl. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    "Moses E. Newsom, maybe Hertford Co., NC"
  - Brown, Thomas C., Jr. (Box 1, Folder 6)
    "TX"
  - Brylinski, Dorothy. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    "This is the other Newsom line. John Newsom - Margaret Reason."
  - Brentlinger, Carol. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - City, Evelyn D.. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Compiled Histories of Newsom, Newsham, Newsum, Newsome, and Nuzum Families Who Came to America, compiled by Rudolph J. Nothdurft, Jr., 2004. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Creed, Paul. (Box 1, Folder 11)
    "Stokes Co. NC"
  - Dell, Mary Alice Newsom. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    "Harrison Newsom"
  - Dilley, Kristy. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    "3094 William Jordan Newsom, b. 1838, Wayne Co. NC -> Carroll Co. MO. Has details of his Civil War pensions. See Darla Myers."
  - Edwards, Linda. (Box 1, Folder 14)
    "Simon Newsom -> Kincheon Newsom"
  - Estelle438 [email screen name]. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    "Clairborne Newsom. Also Thomas Wyche Newsome. See St. Arnaul."
  - Family group sheets. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Foerster, Margaret Vason. (Box 1, Folder 17)
    "Will of Rebecca Newsom."
  - Ford, Candy. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Garr, Gene. (Box 1, Folder 19)
    "Norfleet. John Newsom."
  - Gates, Mary. (Box 1, Folder 20)
    "Silas Newsom. Solomon Newsom. Sent some of Dr. George Newsome papers to her."
  - George, K. S. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Golden, Larry. (Box 1, Folder 22)
    "Solomon Newsom, GA"
  - Goodman, Vivian. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Griffith, Laura. (Box 1, Folder 24)
    "Eldridge Newsom #802 Surry County, VA -> Madison Co. TN"
  - Harris, Gayle. (Box 1, Folder 25)
    "Moses Newsome GA, NC, LA, TX"
  - Haskin, Carl. (Box 1, Folder 26)
    "Allen Lawson Newsome"
  - Henderson, Nancy. (Box 1, Folder 27)
    "William Newsome, Stokes Co. NC"
  - Hollingsworth, Jerry. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Irwin, Barbara. (Box 1, Folder 29)
    "GA"
  - Johnston, David T. (Box 1, Folder 30-31)
    "Re: Shirley Perkins, Wayne Co. NC"
  - Jones, Kyle. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Johnson, Betsy. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Johnson, Texann. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    "Joel Newsom #854 and Rebecca Dickerson"
  - Jolly, Colleen Newsome. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Hatke, Kyra Jo. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    "Pearson Newsom IN, Harrison D. Newsom #2519?"
  - Lake, Deborah. (Box 1, Folder 37)
    "3514 James Newsom - see Boone -> KY"
  - Lande, Nancy Newsom. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Larkin, Laura. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Lawrence, Betty. (Box 1, Folder 40)
    "Thomas Newsom VA"
  - Loos, Peggy. (Box 1, Folder 41)
    "Ransome Newsom"
  - Lucas. (Box 1, Folder 42-43)
  - Maloney, Maxine. (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Margaret-Jeanne. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Miller, Marian. (Box 1, Folder 46)
    "Newsom Town, Davidson Co. NC"
  - Miller, Marian and Rodney. (Box 1, Folder 47)
    "Randolph Co. NC. Davidson Co. NC, Newsome Town.
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Moore, Nancy. (Box 1, Folder 49)
    "Moses Newsom. Hosea Newsom. Charles Newsom m. Pruden."
  - Murauskas, Paul. (Box 1, Folder 50)
    "Re: Tom Kasinger. Newsom - Ahoskie, NC. Boone. Britton."
  - Myers, Darla. (Box 1, Folder 51)
    "Carroll Co. MO"
  - Nail, Anita Newsom. (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Newsome correspondence. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Newsom, Creech. (Box 1, Folder 54)
    "Hartford Co. NC"
  - Newsom, David D. (Dr.). (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Newsom, Donald. (Box 1, Folder 56)
    "Photo of Davenport and Arminda Newsom"
  - Newsom, Ed. (Box 1, Folder 57)
    "Balaam Newsom b. 1824"
  - Newsom family documents from Texas branch. (Box 1, Folder 58-59)
  - The Newsom Family in America (with Special Attention to the Indiana-Quaker Branch" October 1964 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Newsom, Hosea. (Box 1, Folder 61)
    "I always thought that Hosea Newsom of Hertford Co. NC was the key to one of the Newsom branches I was researching. This is a special collection of emails."
  - Newsom, Hoyett. (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Newsom, John/Susannah/William/Eldridge. (Box 1, Folder 63)
    "TN. A collection of emails."
  - Newsom, Joseph. (Box 1, Folder 64)
    "Bertie Co. NC"
  - Newsom, Joshua E. (Box 1, Folder 65)
    "Harold Edward Newsom b. California. Trying to find father's relatives."
  - Newsom, Lewis/Harrison. (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Newsom, Lucy. (Box 1, Folder 67)
    "Researchers interested in Lucy Newsom."
  - Newsom, Marilyn. (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - The Newsom Newsome Family Genealogy and History, by Rudolph Julius Nothdurft, Jr., 13 September 2004 (bound copy). (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The Newsom Newsome Family Genealogy and History, by Rudolph Julius Nothdurft, Jr., 13 September 2004 (master copy). (Box 2, Folder 2-6)
  - Newsom, Rebecca. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    "GA->TX. Probably related to Alfred Alford Newsom 4133"
  - Newsom researchers. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Newsom, Sid. (Box 2, Folder 9)
    "Papers sent by Dr. George Newsome Jr. Map of Richneck Plantation, Surry Co. VA"
  - Newsom, Thomas. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    "Mary Ann Thomas. TX. Manuscript by Carl Newsome. Purley TX"
  - Newsom, Thomas. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    "Genealogy"
  - Newsom - unidentified. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Newsom wills. (Box 2, Folder 13-15)
  - Newsome, Bob. (Box 2, Folder 16)
    "Harrison Newsom #2519. KY. FM Bob Newsome Moorhead KY"
  - Newsome, Bob. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Newsome, Charles W. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    "Lewis N. -> Tivis Newberry Newsom"
  - Newsome, Cyril. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Newsome documents and excerpts from books with family info. (Box 2, Folder 20-23)
  - Newsome family - Ahoskie, NC branch. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - The Newsome Family, compiled in 1907, updated 1927. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Newsome, Gavin. (Box 2, Folder 26)
    "Mayor San Francisco"
  - Newsome, George L., Jr. (Dr.) (Box 2, Folder 27-29)
  - Newsome, Homer R. (Box 2, Folder 30)
    "John Newsome b. 1764. Clairborne Newsom. 3718 John Newsome."
  - Newsome, John. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Newsome, Kevin. (Box 2, Folder 32)
    "Good book on the Newsome line from William Newsom through Hertford Co. NC"
  - Newsome, Larry. (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Newsome, Mildred Langston (photo provided by Mildred N. Waller). (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Newsome, Nannie. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Newsome, Paul. (Box 2, Folder 36)
    "Ahoskie NC"
  - Newsome, Tony. (Box 2, Folder 37)
    "Figgures (sic) Newsom NC"
  - Newsome, William H. (b. ca. 1400), genealogy. (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Newsum. (Box 2, Folder 39)
    "Early research paper for the Newsome family book."
  - North Carolina census. (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Obrant, Susan. (Box 2, Folder 41)
    "Jane Newsom TN"
  - Parker, Wesley. (Box 2, Folder 42)
    "Joab N-. Norfleet N-. Elizabeth Ancillly N- m. James Ireland Rippetoe MO. William went to Texas."
  - People who want books. (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Perkins, Jo Anne. (Box 2, Folder 44)
    "Harrison Newsom KY. Contains photos of her family."
  - Pollard, Norma. (Box 2, Folder 45)
    "Re: Don Dunnington"
  - Porter, Catherine. (Box 2, Folder 46)
    "James William Newsom TN - Book. Lewis Newsom genealogy. William Newsom genealogy."
  - Pusser, Kenty. (Box 3, Folder 1)
    "Hosea. Hertford Co. and KY - Caldwell"
  - Rogers, Lori. (Box 3, Folder 2)
    "John Newsom b. c. 1797 in NC. McCracken Co. KY"
  - Sims, Tammy. (Box 3, Folder 3)
    "John Newsom #3304. Patsy Alford #3305"
  - Size, John Robert. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Smith, Hugh. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Spearman, Louise. (Box 3, Folder 6)
    "Jefferson Davis Newsom. Grayson Co. TX"
  - St. Arnaul, Richard. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Stalker, Tomme. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    "Julian Newsom 662"
  - Steider, Nancy E. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    "Ann Newsom b. TN d. MO"
  - Taylor, Carolyn. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    "James Newsom b. 1792 GA. Joseph Ducksworth Newsom b. 1828 LA"
  - Thomas, Mary Ann. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Thomas, Robin R. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    "Athens, GA"
  - Thompson, Sue. (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Turner, Herbert. (Box 3, Folder 14)
    "Hosea Newsom genealogy. Charles2144 Newsom. John Newsom"
  - Weaver, Lori. (Box 3, Folder 15)
    "Isaac Newsom GA -> MS"
  - West, Patricia. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Whipker, Don. (Box 3, Folder 17)
    "Indiana Newsom. Joel Newsom genealogy. David Newsom Jr. genealogy. Amanda Newsom genealogy. Willis Newsom genealogy. Cader (sic?) Newsom genealogy. Daniel Newsom genealogy."
  - White, Rochelle. (Box 3, Folder 18)
    "See Linda Edwards. Kinchen Newsom. Washington Co. GA"
  - Wink, P. (Box 3, Folder 19)
    "P. Wink. Gilliam see Paul Murauskas"
  - Zetta [__] and Len Stokes Butts. (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - AL. (Box 3, Folder 21)
    "I left this state to Dr. George Newsome Jr. but collected odd emails on Newsom's in the state."
  - AR. (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - CA. (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - FL. (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - GA. (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - IN. (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - KY. (Box 3, Folder 27)
    "Newsom genealogy is really messed up in KY"
  - LA. (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - MS. (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - MO. (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - NC - Hertford Co. (Box 3, Folder 31)
    "Where my Newsom family is located but never connected to Newsom's main branch."
  - NC. (Box 3, Folder 32)
    "William Newsom genealogy"
  - OH. (Box 3, Folder 33)
    "House haunted by a Newsom"
  - OK. (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - SC. (Box 3, Folder 35)
    "William Joel Newsom genealogy"
  - TN. (Box 3, Folder 36)
    "Map to Newsom Mill west of Nashville, TN. William Newsom genealogy"
  - TX. (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - VA. (Box 3, Folder 38)
    "William Newsom genealogy from 1400 -> VA"